TEJ PRASAD SUBEDI

608-5 Greystone Drive, Scarborough ON M1K5J5 Phone: 647-334-8509 Email: tejsubedi@gmail.com | GitHub: https://github.com/tejsubedi LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/tejsubedi/ Portfolio: https://portfoliotejsubedi.herokuapp.com/

SUMMARY

Results-driven, full stack developer with a background in information technology for 10 years. A self-motivated, ambitious, and dedicated Individual, with proven comprehension of full-stack applications. Dedicated to building interactive and user-centered desktop web application and android web application designs. Excellent written and oral communication skills.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Advance knowledge of HTML and CSS coding with Bootstrap, Materialize frame
 and web authoring tools such as Dreamweaver. Demonstrated knowledge of
 Internet/web applications, multimedia, graphic design, video editing, email-Blasts
 and FTP, as well as experience with software, such as Adobe Creative Suite/Cloud,
 Acrobat ProDC, Microsoft Office, content management system SharePoint2013,
 databases.
- Expert knowledge of online branding, design, communication and publishing that led to the improvement of the website
- Fully experienced with Social Media and Website trends and platforms such as YouTube, Twitter, LinkedIn, Facebook, and Instagram.
- PHP, MYSQL, ASP.Net, C#, Java, Python, .Net framework 3.5,4 and 4.5, Web Services, SOAP, HTML/DHTML XML, XSL, XSLT, Dreamweaver, Xpath, DTD, DOM, AJAX, JOUERY.
- Modern JavaScript (ES6+),web-based UI with React and Redux, Modern technologies Node.js, Express, microservices, containers, GitHub, Heroku, Typescript, SQL Server 20016, IIS 6,7, Lotus Notes, Joomla. Windows 10, Microsoft Office 2016, Exchange Server 2016, Active Directory, SQL Server 2016, Macintosh OS X Yosemite, Linux ,Citrix Server, MS-Access, SQL,Oracle 12c

HOW DO I QUALIFY?

Web Communication Knowledge & Skills:

- As the Web Administrator of Freelance Software Developer for Internet and Intranet websites, knowledgeable of web publishing, architecture and building amazing web. As well as communication planning, web development to build, coordinate, and manage web posting of communications products and services.
- Ongoing ability to interpret legislative requirements and Internet/intranet standards and policies, such as AODA, government standards, and international web accessibility standards, such as W3C WCAG 2.0 and WCAG2.1.
- Written Website Governance, Style guide, Accessibility Strategy and Blog Charter documents for Senior Management.
- Ability to learn new skills and new technologies, passion for building high

performance web sites and web applications and provide creative solutions to technical problems.

Communication & Interpersonal Skills:

- Demonstrated written communication skills to review and edit web content, and developed a two level Quality Assurance Process to ensure accurate, concise, and grammatically correct published content.
- Demonstrated oral communication skills and delivered presentations to Senior Managers.
- Provided training for Web Editing, AODA and government standards to selected Freelance staff.
- As a Web Administrator, successfully implemented a Work Ticket System to improve publishing efficiencies and improved relationships in various Areas, through regular consultation meetings and managing expectations. As well as coordinated the web end of projects such as the Fraud Hotline for Senior Management.

HOW DO I QUALIFY?

- As a Web administrator, developed and coordinated all communication strategy and rollouts (digital and print). Delegated various tasks to communication officers.
- Demonstrated advisory skills to provide subject-matter expertise on the planning and development of web communications programs and products with initiatives such User engagement.
- Developed website processes for AODA, content intake, publication and tracking by influencing change management, to improve website workflow through content management integration.

Analytical & Problem Solving Skills:

- Skilled in Google Analytics to interpret web and social media (Twitter) metrics, usage patterns, and provided stakeholder feedback to identify opportunities, and potential issues with Freelance websites and to risk manage them,
- Problem solving skills to identify solutions for unexpected website problems that occur.
- Demonstrated ability to analyze and determine a client's business requirements and negotiate design solutions. Examples would be the redesign of the and it is to be more streamlined and User-friendly.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Web Administrator/Developer | Freelance Company

2013 – present

- Designed and Developed Intranet social media web application called Yammer using HTML,CSS, JavaScript, Node.js, React, ASP.Net, SQL server and MongoDB
- Design and maintaining web page content and templates for Mobile devices as per Rogers standard
- Web application migration services include porting applications to a new technology platform, database and server porting, data migration, standalone-to-web migration of legacy applications;

• Software audit and testing of applications including code reviews, functionality-to-requirements verification, GUI usability and software standards compliance testing and performance/security/stability testing;

- Provide web application maintenance and support services aimed at ensuring stable and uninterrupted operation of the system. Which include problems analysis, resolution and application enhancement;
- Maintenance, test and debugging of existing Web applications such as IP Control system and Technical Support Web sites;
- Provided reverse engineering of existing systems, understanding their business functionality and technical architecture and introduced new/enhanced business logic and improved performance.

Database Administrator | Al Safeer Group of Companies

2009 - 2013

- Formulated of internal inventory controls, policy to comply, install and maintain the
 performance of database servers implementing the command of SQL and SQL server
 tools.
- Learned to provide insight and robust solutions to support the database process and optimizing database security through various access controls.
- Works with the business to ensure compliance and effective control of database security, backup and recovery.
- Learned various tools of web technology JAVA, HTML and CSS with the web development team and implement of SQL database.

System Administrator Pioneer Plastic Factory L.L.C. Umm Al Quwain

2007 - 2008

- Design and develop programs as needed to meet user needs and business requirements.
- Web Administration for internal Incident management web application called Admin3
- Managed DB Functions, procedures, cursors, Triggers, Exception Handling, and created packages.
- Prepared, ran complex ad-hoc queries for vendors, stores and generate customized reports
- Analyze information requests and discuss with user to assemble all elements required to produce the requested information.
- Code, test and implement programs using appropriate programming languages, such as PL/SQL, PHP, and JavaScript.
- Extended post implementation issues, resolved production issues, and critical data fixed.
- Maintain current documentation on all programs, systems, and procedures.
- Maintain and modify existing programs and web applications as required.
- Analyzed, tuned SQL queries used Explain Plan, SQL optimized performance
- Troubleshoot problems to determine root cause and corrected.

• Reviews user requirements and needs for new software and performs analysis, design, implementation, installation and training related to new software developed or acquired.

- Provide technical assistance and advice to end user programming community Analyze and define business requirements, participate in the selection, and implement new functionality, applications and modules within the SQL Server database.
- Configured Internet Protocols DNS,SMTP,POP3, IMAP, HTTP, HTTPS, SNMP and Active directory

PROJECTS

Event Hunter

GitHub: https://github.com/bootcampcoder/project-1/ **Deployment**: https://bootcampcoder.github.io/project-1/

- **About**: This application is about to find free events within 10km of user's location by implementing event application.
- Role: plugin Google maps application with the location searching of events.
- **Technologies:** JavaScript, jQuery, Firebase Authentication, materialize, bootstrap, html, moment.js and Google Maps.

Zombie Blasters

GitHub: https://github.com/Esther12/The-Wall

Deployment: https://zombie-blasters.herokuapp.com/

- **About**: It implements a shooting game. If you shoot a civilian, you will lose a life.
- **Role**: create Sequelize-ORM query model and login-signup page with implementing passport authentication and bcrypt.js.
- **Technologies**: JavaScript, jQuery, GreenSock-JS, Node.js, MySQL, Sequelize, Passport, bcrypt.js, CSS, HTML, session.

Link to Lift

GitHub: https://github.com/Indian-Indepth/link-to-lift

Deployment: https://link-to-lift.herokuapp.com/

- **About:** Provide personal training via connecting to the favorite trainer.
- Role: create payment method and generate html pdf as backend developer and integrated backend code with frontend.
- **Technologies**: JavaScript, ReactJS, Google Authentication, Bulma, Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB, Braintree payments platform, html-pdf.

EDUCATION

UofT SCS Coding Boot Camp

UofT School of Continuing Studies, Toronto, ON, Canada 2019 - 2019 A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

Computer Programmer Analyst

George Brown College, Toronto, ON, Canada

2016 - 2019

A 3 years' intensive program focused on gaining technical programming and software designing skills with emphasis on HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, PHP, C#, .NET, Java, Python, Angular, ReactJS, Agile methodologies and so on.

Bachelor's Degree in Business Management

Tribhuvan University, Kathmandu, Nepal

1999 - 2002

A 3 years' intensive program focused on business, economics, accounting and finance